John Isom

iohn@johnisom.dev iohnisom.dev iohnisom iohnisom

Software Engineer with rich experience working with and building microservice architectures with Node.js, Ruby, RabbitMQ, and more. I do my best work and love working on the backend, working with the various systems and architectures, and solving the unique problems there.

Professional Experience

Software Engineer, *Prime Trust*

Jan 2022 – present

- Reduced monthly operating costs by \$120k by integrating a new ledger system with millions of transactions and by improving business logic
- Researched and ran learning sessions for Docker & Docker Compose and Kafka
- Set up Kafka and set up data pipelines between multiple Ruby and Typescript services
- Dockerified the monolith and pioneered the use of Docker in all future services
- Created brand-new TypeScript Node.js services with express.js and Nest.js, automating manual processes to be more accurate and efficient
- Worked with Staff Engineers to set up inter-service authentication
- Onboarded and mentored a new teammate, ran meetings, and created an optional and successful biweekly team social hour

Software Development Engineer III, *GoDaddy / Re:amaze*

Nov 2020 – Jan 2022

- Led the adoption of a new attachment backend in our Rails app, managing and executing the seamless migration of 20 million file attachments with no downtime or performance issues using multi-threading
- Created a new column in a database table with 118 million+ records and backfilled the values with minimal downtime
- Spearheaded migrating a massive monolithic Rails app from Rails 5 → 6
- Designed and added drop-in encryption for sensitive fields in our database with full backward compatibility and no downtime
- Teamed up with another engineer to publish snapshots of our 1.7TB database into AWS Data Lake

Co-Creator & Software Engineer, Maestro Framework

2020

Open-source easy-to-use framework for quickly bootstrapping, deploying, and rapidly iterating serverless orchestration workflows with AWS IAM, AWS Lambda, and AWS Step Functions.

- Created a framework that is over 60x faster to deploy than the fastest competitor (AWS SAM)
- Co-authored a detailed case study that explores the area of serverless orchestration, existing solutions in the problem space, and the process of creating Maestro (https://maestro-framework.github.io/ 🗷)

Languages and Technologies

Languages (JavaScript (ES5 & ES6+), TypeScript, Ruby, SQL),

Frameworks (Rails, express.js, Next.js, Roda; Sequel (Ruby)),

Cloud (AWS Step Functions; S3; Lambda; EC2; Docker & Docker Compose; Kubernetes, Kafka; RabbitMQ),

Other (Linux, Git & GitHub; GitHub actions, Networking stack, OOP)

Education

Launch School, Software Engineering

2019 - 2020

A rigorous online school for software engineers with a Mastery-Based Learning pedagogy. launchschool.com/employers 🗅

Western Governers University,

B.S. of Computer Science (incomplete)

While working, completed half of a B.S. of Computer Science. Left in good academic standing.